[{"stepName": "Identify Motion of objects", "stepNumber": 1, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many moving objects are present?", "options": [3, 1, 5, 6], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": [""], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "How many strings are there?", "options": [2, 0, 1, 5], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "tobeshown": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Write FBD equation for each Moving block", "stepNumber": 2, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the y-direction", "options": ["+T\u2081+10=1a\u2081", "-T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "-T\u2081+10=1a\u2081", "+T\u2081-10=1a\u2081"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "+T\u2081-10=1a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "T\u2083: Tension in white string"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for red block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on red block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 upwards", "T\u2081 downwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the y-direction", "options": ["+T\u2081+10=1a\u2081", "-T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "-T\u2081+10=1a\u2081", "+T\u2081-10=1a\u2081"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, "], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: 10", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the y-direction", "options": ["+10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "+10-T\u2081-T\u2082=1a\u2082", "-10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "-10-T\u2081-T\u2082=1a\u2082"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "+10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "T\u2083: Tension in white string"], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for yellow block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "answer": 2}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on yellow block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2081 upwards", "T\u2081 downwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on yellow block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2082 upwards", "T\u2082 downwards"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block in the y-direction", "options": ["+10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "+10-T\u2081-T\u2082=1a\u2082", "-10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "-10-T\u2081-T\u2082=1a\u2082"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2081, ", "Downward Forces: T\u2082, 10", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of blue block in the y-direction", "options": ["+80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "+80+T\u2082=8a\u2083", "-80+T\u2082=8a\u2083", "-80-T\u2082=8a\u2083"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": -300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "+80-T\u2082=8a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["T\u2081: Tension in pink string", "T\u2082: Tension in red string", "T\u2083: Tension in white string"], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for blue block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "answer": 1}, {"question": "What is the force at this point of intersection on blue block?", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["T\u2082 upwards", "T\u2082 downwards"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["Upward Forces: ", "Downward Forces: ", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"]}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of blue block in the y-direction", "options": ["+80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "+80+T\u2082=8a\u2083", "-80+T\u2082=8a\u2083", "-80-T\u2082=8a\u2083"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082"], "type": "advance", "tobeshown": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Forces: T\u2082, ", "Downward Forces: 80", "Rightward Forces: ", "Leftward Forces: "], "showfcheading": ["Blue block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083"]}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Equations", "stepNumber": 3, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "+a\u2081-a\u2082=0", "-a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "-a\u2081-a\u2082=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "-a\u2081+a\u2082=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["a\u2081: acceleration of red block in y-direction", "a\u2082: acceleration of yellow block in y-direction", "a\u2083: acceleration of blue block in y-direction"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is the number of parts which change length in the pink string?", "options": [5, 4, 2, 3], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 0}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for pink string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2081", "-a\u2081"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2082 for pink string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2082", "-a\u2082"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for pink string?", "options": ["+a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "+a\u2081-a\u2082=0", "-a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "-a\u2081-a\u2082=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083"], "showfc": ["l\u2081 + l\u2082 = constant", "l\u2081'' = -a\u2081", "l\u2082'' = +a\u2082"], "showfcheading": ["Pink string"], "tobeshown": 0, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0"], "type": "advance"}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for red string?", "options": ["+a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "+a\u2082-a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082-a\u2083=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "-a\u2082+a\u2083=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["a\u2081: acceleration of red block in y-direction", "a\u2082: acceleration of yellow block in y-direction", "a\u2083: acceleration of blue block in y-direction"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"], "tobeshown": 1}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for red string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2082", "-a\u2082"], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is double derivative of change in l\u2081 for red string:", "tobeshown": 0, "options": ["+a\u2083", "-a\u2083"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0"], "type": "advance", "showfc": ["l\u2081 = constant"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"]}, {"question": "What is the constraint equation for red string?", "options": ["+a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "+a\u2082-a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "-a\u2082-a\u2083=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 300, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0"], "showfc": ["l\u2081 = constant", "l\u2081'' = -a\u2082 +a\u2083"], "showfcheading": ["Red string"], "tobeshown": 0, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "Red string: -a\u2082+a\u2083=0"], "type": "advance"}]}, {"stepName": "Final Answers", "stepNumber": 4, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What are the final accelerations, tensions and normal reactions?", "options": ["a\u2081= 8.0, a\u2082= -8.0, a\u2083= -8.0, T\u2081= 18.0, T\u2082= 16.0, T\u2083= 36.0", "a\u2081= -18.0, a\u2082= -36.0, a\u2083= -8.0, T\u2081= -16.0, T\u2082= 8.0, T\u2083= 8.0", "a\u2081= 8.0, a\u2082= -36.0, a\u2083= -8.0, T\u2081= -16.0, T\u2082= 8.0, T\u2083= -18.0", "a\u2081= -18.0, a\u2082= -16.0, a\u2083= -36.0, T\u2081= 8.0, T\u2082= -8.0, T\u2083= 8.0"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "finalanswer", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "Red string: -a\u2082+a\u2083=0"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": [], "tobeshown": 1, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, a\u2083, T\u2081, T\u2082, ", "Red block: +T\u2081-10=1a\u2081", "Yellow block: +10-T\u2081+T\u2082=1a\u2082", "Blue block: +80-T\u2082=8a\u2083", "Pink string: -a\u2081+a\u2082=0", "Red string: -a\u2082+a\u2083=0", "Final Answers: a\u2081= 8.0, a\u2082= -8.0, a\u2083= -8.0, T\u2081= 18.0, T\u2082= 16.0, T\u2083= 36.0"]}]}]